pjtv.com 2018-06-25

# Privacy Policy | PJ Media

06-24-2018 07:05:35 PM -0700

06-24-2018 01:33:26 PM -0700

06-23-2018 11:28:09 AM -0700

06-22-2018 05:46:20 PM -0700

06-22-2018 09:10:32 AM -0700

It looks like you've previously blocked notifications. If you'd like to receive them, please update your browser permissions. 

Desktop Notifications are   | 

Get instant alerts on your desktop. 

Turn on desktop notifications? 

The Latest. Delivered Daily. 

Your friends will think you read the whole newspaper 

In addition to the Privacy Policy and Rights applicable to all users of our Websites, California residents have some additional rights.

If you are a California resident and you provided your email address to PJ Media, LLC ("PJM,” “Us” or “We”), then, once each calendar year, you may submit a written request for information about the information we shared, if any, with other companies for their use in direct marketing. To submit your written request, please send an E-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#473022252a263433223507372d2a22232e266924282a) with "Request for California Privacy" in the subject line.

Within 30 days of receiving your request, we will send you a list of the names and addresses of these other companies during the immediately preceding calendar year.

We reserve our right not to respond to requests sent more than once in a calendar year, or requests submitted to an address other than the one posted in this notice.

Please note that the California "Shine the Light" law does not cover all information sharing. Our disclosure only includes information covered by the law.

 **PJ MEDIA PRIVACY POLICY**

This policy was last updated June 2013

 **GENERAL**

PJ Media, LLC., dba PJMedia, PJTV and Next Generation (“PJM”), is committed to maintaining the privacy of personal information that you provide to us when using [www.PJMedia.com](http://pjmedia.com/), [www.PJTV.com](http://www.pjtv.com/) and [NextGeneration.TV](http://www.nextgeneration.tv/)(the “Site” or “Sites”). The term Site includes any additional websites we may subsequently implement. This Privacy Policy describes how we treat personal information received about you when you visit or become a member of any of our Sites.

We may make content or services from other websites available to you from links located on the Sites. These other websites are not subject to this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you review the privacy policy at each such website to determine how that site protects your privacy.

 **NOTICE CONCERNING CHILDREN**

 **PLEASE NOTE** : We are general audience Sites, and do not direct any of our content specifically at children under 13 years of age. We understand and are committed to respecting the sensitive nature of children’s privacy online. If we learn or have reason to suspect that a Site user is under age 13, we will promptly delete any personal information in that user’s account.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

 **General** : When you register, and at other times, we will collect information from you.  This information falls into two main categories: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

 **Personally Identifiable Information (PII)** is any information collected through the Sites that identifies or can be used to identify, contact, or locate you.  PII would include your full name, address, and credit-card number.  PII may include your email address if you have chosen not to use an anonymous email address (e.g.,: some people have their full name in their email address, or have a personal website URL in their email address). Your email address is your “User Name” on our websites. It is not visible to other users. In some states even an anonymous email address is considered PII.  PII may include your Screen Name, if you have chosen not to use an anonymous screen name. Your Screen Name is visible to other users when you post comments.

We do not knowingly collect PII from children under the age of eighteen.

Although PII is collected through our Sites, your billing information (full name, address and associated credit card number) are not stored on our servers.  We use the services of Paypal to process credit card payments.  Please refer to Paypal’s privacy statement which can be found [here](https://cms.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/marketingweb?cmd=_render-content&fli=true&content_ID=ua/Privacy_full&locale.x=en_US) for information about the storage of your name, address and credit card information.

Your email address and user password are stored on our server. We also collect other non-PII facts about your computers, profession, interests and similar information.

 **Surveys:** We may conduct occasional online surveys. For example, when you’re within one of our Sites, you may see a pop-up window or button offering you the optional opportunity of participating in a survey. These surveys are entirely voluntary and you may easily decline to participate.  If you do participate, you may be asked to provide additional information.

 **Site Usage Information:** We automatically collect IP addresses and Site usage information from you when you visit the Sites . This information helps us evaluate how our visitors and members use and navigate our Sites including the number and frequency of visitors and members to each Web page, and the length of their visits.

Additionally we may collect usage information that is tied to Personally Identifiable Information for purposes of subscription tracking and enforcement, for special features, or to provide enhanced member products and services.

 **Help Desk Information:** Should you contact our Customer Support System with a question or technical concern, we will create and then store a customer support “ticket” that you will fill out.  This is your support profile.  This profile may include first name, last name, phone number, email address, and if needed to address your concern, city/state/zip and address.

 **HOW WE USE INFORMATION COLLECTED**

We may use information in the following ways:

  * Credit card information is used only to process, validate and verify memberships and subscriptions;
  * For any purpose, if we announce the purpose in advance;
  * To provide notifications about new or existing products and services, special offers from us and from third-party providers, through email, pop-ups or other technology;
  * To provide advertisements to you through the Sites, email messages, text messages, applications, or other methods of communication;
  * To operate and enhance existing features or develop new features, products and services;
  * To provide Third Party Service Providers (see description of Third Party Service Providers, below) with aggregate information about our user base and usage patterns;
  * To allow us to personalize the content that you and others see based on personal characteristics or preferences.

We may combine the information that we collect from you on the Sites with information that you provide to us in connection with your use of our other products, services and Sites.

We may also share our membership list with organizations which provide information, services or products from which we believe our members will benefit. Information on canceling any account or opting out of our email lists can be found in the “Your Rights” section below.

We may hire other companies to perform services on our behalf including, without limitation, facilitating some aspects of the Sites, serving advertisements, sending e-mail, and fulfilling purchase requests. These other companies may be supplied with or have access to your Personally Identifiable Information solely for the purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf.  Please see the following provider privacy policies:

We may use third parties, called Third Party Service Providers, to provide premium features such as links to sources of additional information or to conduct surveys. These Third Party Service Providers may be supplied with or have access to your Personally Identifiable Information solely for the purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf. They may also collect additional Personally Identifiable Information directly on their websites. They may also collect and use non-Personally Identifiable Information about your visits to the Sites and other websites in order to present custom information that may be of interest to you.  If you would like more information about this practice or to opt out of having this information used by some Third Party Service Providers, [please visit here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp).

We may disclose and use Personally Identifiable Information and other information in special circumstances where it is necessary to enforce our User and Member Agreement or Terms of Service (for example, when necessary to protect our intellectual property rights). We may also disclose or use your Personally Identifiable Information as well as other information when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires us to do so.

 **USER CONTENT**

 **Comments:** The Comments section of any Site provides you with an opportunity to tell us what you think about our content, and read what other readers have to say, and possibly to upload other content such as user-generated videos. When you register to use our comments feature, you are giving us the right to make your comments public and to make public the screen name you choose.

 **Other User Submitted Content:** We may provide you with the opportunity to submit other content to our Sites for viewing by our readers, such as videos, photographs, blog posts or articles.  If you choose to submit material to us, we may ask for information about you and the material you submitted.  We may make public any information that you provide including your name, location and e-mail address.

 **Other User Submitted Information:** We may provide you with the opportunity to submit and save information relating to our Sites and various areas on our Sites, such as books you’ve read, movies seen, reviews, etc. Submitting this information is voluntary. You will be told which information is visible to either other users of that area, or the public. Please read this information carefully so you can choose whether you wish to submit this information or not.

 **MEMBER MESSAGES**

If you subscribe to any members-only area of the Sites, to special email lists, or to any other voluntary subscription-based program, you may occasionally receive email messages about the Sites that are intended to assist you in making the most out of your subscription. These member messages contain a link that you may use to opt out of receiving further member messages. You may also decline to receive them by contacting [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7a090f0a0a15080e3a0a10171f1e131b54191517).

 **YOUR RIGHTS**

 **Ability To Choose:** You may, of course, decline to submit Personally Identifiable Information through the PJM Sites, in which case we may not be able to provide all of our services to you. You may update or correct your personal profile information and email preferences at any time by visiting your profile page. Please note that media files uploaded by you cannot be removed and remain subject to our User and Member Agreement and Terms of Service.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you profile access or making corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

If you would like more information about opting out or having your information used by some Third Party Service Providers, [please visit here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp).

 **How to Review, Correct or Delete Your Information:** You may review, and update the Personally Identifiable Information/registration information that you have provided to us by contacting Customer Service at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0d7e787d7d627f794d7d67606869646c236e6260). You may also delete your account through Customer Service at the links provided.

 **Email and Newsletter Opt-Out:** We give our users the option to sign up for email lists and newsletters.  However, you may change your mind about a subscription, or we may make a mistake and add you to a mailing list you didn’t request.  In either case, you can always click on the “opt-out” link at the bottom of each email or newsletter we might send.

 **COOKIES AND WEB BEACONS**

We employ cookie technology. Read our Cookie Disclosure Statement for more information about our use of cookies. We use web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) on our Sites in order to recognize users and assess traffic patterns. We also include Web beacons in our e-mail messages including newsletters in order to count how many e-mail messages have been opened.

 **THIRD PARTY CONTENT ON THE SITES**

When you view any third party content such as a survey or supplemental references on our Sites or on other sites, our Third Party Service Provider may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. The Sites and our providers may also use Web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) to note which Services pages you visit after viewing our ads. The information that is collected through the use of these images is not personally identifiable and is used only to track response to our advertising efforts.

 **SECURITY**

The Personally Identifiable Information we collect about you is stored in limited-access servers. We will maintain safeguards to protect the security of these servers and your Personally Identifiable Information.

 **DATA RETENTION**

We retain your information for as long as necessary to permit us to use it for the purposes that we have communicated to you and comply with applicable law or regulations.

 **POLICY MODIFICATIONS**

When we make any material change to this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by posting a notice on the home page of our Sites that the policy has been updated and by changing the date on this page noting when the policy was last updated.

 **TRANSFER TO U.S.**

PJM is hosted in the United States.  If you are a member or user accessing PJM from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of PJM (which is governed by U.S. law), this Privacy Notice, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer.

 **IN THE EVENT OF MERGER, SALE, OR BANKRUPTCY**

In the event that PJM is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected from our members and users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors’ rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#35464045455a474175455f5850515c541b565a58).

 **COOKIE DISCLOSURE STATEMENT**

Cookies are a common type of technology used by most large websites.  The following is information that will help you understand the use of cookies.

 **What's a cookie?**

A cookie is a small file that is sent to your computer by a site’s server. A cookie can be a record of your visit to a site, including information such as your User Name, registration information, time of last visit, pages viewed, etc. A cookie created by one site’s servers can be retrieved only by that site’s servers. Thus, information in the PJM cookies is not accessible to other sites. This type of cookie is called a “first party” cookie.

There is another type of cookie called a “third party” cookie. If you are using website A, and website A uses the services of website B, and if website B were to leave a cookie on your machine, that would be considered a “third party” cookie because you are not using website B directly.  Some browsers, for example Internet Explorer, are configured to disallow third party cookies by default.

 **Using PJM**

In order to access PJM successfully, your browser must be set to “accept all cookies.” You can later block cookies from other individual sites if you wish.

If you set your browser to “not accept” any cookies, or if you block our cookies, you will not be able to register or sign in to the Sites because we use cookies to keep track of your sign-in status. We also use cookies to implement the “remember me” feature, which allows you to return to the Sites without having to log in each time. We do this by saving an encrypted version of your credentials in a cookie.

If your browser is not set to accept cookies, then you can still use the Sites, but only as a visitor. Visitors have a limited number of videos that they can watch before registering, so if your browser is not set to accept cookies, you will not be able to watch those additional videos once you reach this limit. Also, if you cannot register you cannot subscribe to the Sites.

We also suggest that you do not navigate the Sites with your browser’s “cookie alert” feature enabled. While you certainly could set your browser to alert you each time a cookie is passed to your machine, you most likely will find the experience of having to respond to frequent cookie alerts quite frustrating while trying to enjoy your subscription. We suggest that you turn the “cookie alert” feature off, or perhaps use the Sites for a short time with it on, once you’ve seen firsthand how we use the technology.

 **Why do we use cookies?**

We use cookies to allow you to move quickly through our Sites. We accomplish this in many ways, using several different cookies. When you first enter our Sites, for example, we use a test cookie to confirm your browser’s ability to retain cookies. Next, we check our database to verify your subscription so you can gain access. A cookie is then temporarily “set” within your browser to allow you to proceed without having to confirm your identity with each subsequent page you request to view.

Without cookie technology, we would not be able to offer you convenient features such as the ability to store your User Name and Password so that you won’t have to sign in each time you come to the Sites.

We use P3P to allow the use of third party cookies within the family of PJM Sites. P3P (Platform for Privacy Preferences Project) is a protocol that allows websites to declare their intended use of information they collect about web browser users. When this is done some of the default restrictions against third party cookies are relaxed. We do this to allow all of our Sites to use a single database of user information , so that once you register with one of our Sites, you will be able to sign in to any of our Sites.

Other cookies that you may receive during your sessions here are from actual Third Party Service Providers. These Third Party Service Providers may use their own cookies in order to serve surveys or premium content on our Sites.

 **Third party cookie information for emails.**

We, or a data provider we have engaged, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content or services. No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies or learn more please go to <http://aboutads.info/choices> or <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

Additionally, emails we send may contain a bit of code known as a "web beacon." This code allows us to understand the time and date of when a user has opened an email and when he/she has utilized a link within the email to visit a website. Our web beacons do not collect personally identifiable information. Users wishing to disable our web beacons should do so by turning images "off" in their email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see your email client for more information.”

 **So what's in it for our members?**

Here's a quick rundown of what we see as the biggest advantages of using cookies:

  * Universal sign in. Once you register with one of our Sites you can use these same credentials on all of our Sites.
  * More convenient access. We won't have to ask you to identify yourself with each new page requested.
  * Fewer Sign-ins. Using our "remember me" feature, you can return to our Sites without having to sign in each time.

 **Will the cookies you send me go away?**

Some of our cookies are long term. If they weren’t, we’d need to ask you for certain information with each new session, such as your User Name. Some cookies do expire after a short period of time. Remember, cookies are small files and won’t pose any significant disk-space concerns on your computer.

In fact, most of PJM cookies expire after 24 hours from their time of issue. Others, such as those required to retain settings you elect (User Name, Password, etc.) will continue to reside on your hard drive for subsequent use by your browser, but are quite small and should not pose any significant disk capacity concern.

You are, of course, free to clear any and all cookies from your hard drive any time you wish; simply search your system for any files named cookie*.* (or similar) and delete these at your discretion. Additionally all major Internet browsers have a feature that allows you to erase cookies. This is usually found in the preferences section of your browser.  Your browser’s “Help” section should allow you to find this feature.

Remember, however, that deleting these cookies means any long-term settings (such as your stored User Name) will need to be provided the next time you want to use one of the Sites.

There are also a number of software and shareware programs available that are designed to periodically purge cookie files from your hard disk. We do not recommend these applications and, as such, cannot address any resulting support issues that may be related to the use of these programs.

Copyright PJ Media® 2013. All Rights Reserved.

http://pjmedia.com/privacy-policy
